Guide to the Ludmir Young Men’s Benevolent Association 0009.002.005b
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
Ludmir Young Men's Benevolent Association
1932-2000
0009.002.005b
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
1.0 Cubic feet 2 Boxes
Immigrants from Ludmir, a town in Eastern Europe, founded the Ludmir Young Men's Benevolent Association in Hartford in 1932. At that time, associations formed by immigrants from particular locales in Europe provided an important support system for new arrivals. During an era when it was difficult for American Jews to obtain life insurance and social services, benevolent associations afforded invaluable assistance to their members. In addition to maintaining a cemetery, the Ludmir group offered social activities and provided charitable assistance to members in need. As time passed, more and more Synagogues came into being and other charitable organizations emerged. As these resources became accessible to Jews, the Association outgrew many of its initial purposes and became strictly a burial society. Ludmir cemetery is located on Tower Ave. in Hartford.
Related Archival Materials note
Brahilover Benevolent Association Organizations: Vertical File
Ludmir
- Series I: Ludmir Records & Manuscripts
  - Articles of Association, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and By-laws, revised, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1997, 1978-1997 (Box 1)
  - Financial/Bank Statements, 1978-1990 (Box 1)
  - Financial/Bank Statements, 1991-1995 (Box 1)
  - Financial/Bank Statements, 1995-2000 (Box 1)
  - Financial/Cancelled checks, 1979-1996 (Box 1)
  - Financial/Cancelled checks, 1997-1999 (Box 1)
  - Financial/Financial Reports, 1951-1976 (Box 1)
  - Financial/Receipts/Atlantic Fence Company, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Financial/Receipts/JML Landscaping, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Financial/Receipts/H.S. Plaut Cemetery Company, Inc., 1997 (Box 1)
- Series II: Ludmir Records & Manuscripts
  - Financial/Receipts/Members 1947-1968, Bound Ledger Book (Box 2)
  - Financial/Receipts/Members 1947-1970, Bound Ledger Book (Box 2)
  - Financial/Receipts/Members 1965-1968, "Money Receipts Manifold Book" (Box 2)
  - Financial/Receipts/Members 1968-1972, "Efficiency Line Money Receipts" (Box 2)
  - Financial/Receipts/Members 1972-1985, Bound volume "Duplicate Rent Receipts" (Box 2)
  - Financial/Receipts/Members, 1971-1990s, 1971-1999 (Box 2)
  - Financial/Tax Exempt Status, undated (Box 2)
  - History, undated (Box 2)
  - Insurance/Liability policies, 1998-2000 (Box 2)
  - Members/List in small blue notebook, 1930s-1980s, 1930-1989 (Box 2)
  - Members/List on small notebook paper, 1933-1999 (Box 2)
  - Members/Obituaries- Newspaper clippings, 1970s-1990s, 1970-1999 (Box 2)
  - Members/Roll of Departed Members/small bound volume, 1933-1997 (Box 2)
  - Memorial Service at the Cemetery, pamphlet compiled and arranged by Rabbi Morris Silverman, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Minute Book, 1964-1973 (Box 2)